http://www.ipa-online.org/privacy-notice

Cookie Notice
This site uses cookies. By continuing to browse this site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies. Review our cookies information for more details.
OK
HomeAboutMission and VisionBoard of DirectorsIPA AffiliatesAwardsIPA Distinguished Service AwardsIPA Junior Research AwardsLuigi Amaducci Memorial AwardIPA News and MediaWorkforce IssuesIPA SecretariatDonate to IPAContact IPAMembershipMembership BenefitsJoin IPAHow to RenewLifetime MembersPublicationsInternational PsychogeriatricsInstructions for ContributorsReprints and SupplementsIPA BulletinIPA Bulletin EditorsSubmission GuidelinesIPA Bulletin Call for EditorsIPA Complete Guides to Behavioral and Psychological Symptoms of Dementia (BPSD)Guide to the Psychiatry of Old AgeEventsEvents CalendarIPA International Congress2020 Virtual CongressPast IPA CongressesIPA Regional MeetingsPast IPA Regional Meetings2017 ConferenceExpert MeetingsWorkshops & SymposiaOnline EducationWebinar SeriesIPA caféForumsProfessional Discipline ForumsNursesOccupational TherapistsPrimary Care PhysiciansPsychologistsSocial WorkersShared Interest ForumsBehavioral and Psychological Symptoms of Dementia (BPSD)CapacityLong-Term CareYoung Onset DementiaSleep & Healthy AgingLearning PortalResearchSponsorsIPA Corporate Partner Program
Privacy Notice
Home  »  Privacy Notice
Privacy Notice
Website Privacy Notice
The International Psychogeriatric Association (IPA) has a strong commitment to privacy, recognizing that we are a public association. This statement outlines the policies and procedures concerning information gathering and dissemination practices for our website.
Collecting and Using User Information
IPA collects information in different ways from those who access our site. We use this information primarily to provide a customized experience as you use our site and do not share this information with third parties. However, we may disclose personal information collected if we have received your permission beforehand or in very special circumstances, such as when we believe that such disclosure is required by law, or in other special cases described below.
Our site uses order forms for customers to request information, products, and services. We collect users’ contact information (e.g., name and e-mail address) and financial information (e.g., account or credit card numbers). Financial information is used to bill the user for products and services and then is deleted from our records in compliance with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS). Contact information from the order form is used to send orders, contact the user regarding any problems with the order, and to provide the user with information about our association, including promotional materials. Users may opt out of receiving future communications at any time by contacting the Secretariat.
Membership Directory
Current IPA members' contact information is made available through the Membership Directory. This information is only available to other current IPA members. Members may opt out of being listed in the Membership Directory; see the Updating User Profile section below.
Disclosure of Personal Information
It is the policy of IPA not to use or share the personal information about users in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses. However, IPA may disclose personal information about users, or information regarding your use of our site, for any reason if, in our sole discretion, we believe that it is reasonable to do so, including: to satisfy laws, such as the Electronic Communications Privacy Act, regulations, or governmental or legal requests for such information; to disclose information that is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our Website Terms of Use or other user policies; to operate the site properly; or to protect IPA and our users.
Updating User Profile
Individuals who have created an account with IPA have the ability to update or change all personal information provided. To do so, users may visit the My Profile section of the IPA website, or email the Secretariat with updated information.
Opt In/Out of Communications
IPA provides individuals the opportunity to opt out of receiving communications from us when we request information about the user. To update these preferences, users may visit the IPA website or email the Secretariat.
Opt In/Out of Membership Directory
IPA also allows our members to opt out of displaying personal information in the Membership Directory. To update these preferences, members may visit the IPA website or email the Secretariat.
Security
Our site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control, but we cannot guarantee that our security measures will prevent third-party "hackers" from illegally obtaining this information.
Cookies
A "cookie" is a small data file that can be placed on your hard drive when you visit certain websites. IPA may use cookies to collect, store, and sometimes track information for statistical purposes, to improve the products and services we provide, or to save your settings and to provide customizable and personalized services. These cookies do not enable third parties to access any of your personal information.
Additionally, be aware that if you visit non-IPA websites where you are prompted to log in or that are customizable, you may be required to accept cookies. Third parties and other non-IPA websites may also use their own cookies. We do not control use of these cookies and expressly disclaim responsibility for information collected through them.
Finally, cookies are used to support Google Analytics functionality for website activity tracking. Google Analytics stores information at Google. Read more about Google Analytics privacy and security information.
Links to Other Sites
This site contains links to other websites. IPA is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each website that collects your personally identifiable information.
Changes to This Policy
IPA reserves the right to revise, amend, or modify this Privacy Policy, our website Terms of Use, and our other policies and agreements at any time and in any manner. Notice of any revision, amendment, or modification will be posted in accordance with our website Terms of Use.
Acknowledgements
CORPORATE COUNCILS
